Guide to the Study Group on Yale College (Dahl Committee) Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Study Group on Yale College (Dahl Committee) records
1953-1972
RU 431
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.25
(17 boxes)
The records consist of drafts, reports, correspondence, research material, and printed matter documenting the work of the Study Group on Yale College (Dahl Committee), which was formed in 1972 to make recommendations concerning the future of Yale College.
Yale University. Study Group on Yale College
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-D (YRG 9-D), Records of Yale College committees.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of drafts, reports, correspondence, research material, and printed matter documenting the work of the Study Group on Yale College (Dahl Committee), which was formed in 1972 to make recommendations concerning the future of Yale College.
Education, Higher; Universities and colleges -- Planning; Dahl, Robert A., 1915-2014; Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Planning; Yale University. President's Office; Yale University. Study Group on Yale College
- Committee records, 1953-1972; Accession 1972-A-008
  - Committee Papers
    - Report of the Study Group of Yale College, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Original Drafts of Sections of Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - First Complete Draft of Report; Recommendations for Second Draft, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Second Draft and Recommendations, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Draft of Final Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Page Proofs of Report, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mnutes; also comments on the first draft of report by faculty member, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters from Faculty and Students, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Letters from Faculty, Students, Alumni, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Indexed Copies of Letters Recieved, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Research Material
    - Admissions:
      - "Admission of Puerto Rican Students to Yale College" - Boricuas Unidos, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - "Admission Policies - Side Effects"American Psychologist, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - "Criteria of Student Success in Yale College" - Hackman, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - "Decision Rule to Categorize Applicants" - Sternberg, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - "Expectancies of Admission for Yale Affiliates…", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - "Muyskens Letter", 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - "Profile of the Yale College Class of 1975", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - "Research in Undergraduate Admissions" - Hoskins and Chauncey, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Statistics for "Accepted/Went Elsewhere", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - "Students Admitted…Who Withdrew to Other Schools", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Advance Placement and Credits Awarded, Class of 1974, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Alumni - Contribution Information, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Alumni Magazine, Yale, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Apter, David E. "The University College", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Athletics: Students in Intramural Sports, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Annotated Bibliography- Ellen Comisso, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Bibliography of Files, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Bumham and Hewitt: "Advanced Placements Scores: Their Predictive Validity'', 1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Burnham, Paul S. "Postgraduate Plans" Class of 1969 and 1970, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Burnham, Paul S. - Summary of the Research Output 1959-1971 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Calendar Plans and Mentorships, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Choate School - Course Descriptions, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Clark, Burton R. - reprints of articles, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Coeducation, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - College Fellowships, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Colleges and Universities
      - Amherst College, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Brown University, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 39 - 40)
      - California, University of, Berkeley, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - California, University of, Santa Cruz, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Chicago, University of, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Dartmouth College, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Evergreen State College, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Hampshire College, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 46 - 47)
      - Harvard College, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 48 - 49)
      - Maryland, University of, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Maryland, University of, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - New Hampshire, University of, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - New York, State University of, College at Old Westbury, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Oberlin College, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - Pennsylvania, University of, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - Princeton University, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - Stanford University, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 58)
      - Trinity College, 1968-1982 (Box 8, Folder 59)
      - Wayne State University, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Wesleyan University, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Wisconsin, University of, 1969-1982 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - The Community Group on Learning (working papers), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Course Evaluations, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Curriculum Research- Jan Costello, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Curriculum Study- Deborah Lee, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Data Notebook of Dahl Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 67 - 68)
    - Delgado, Jose: Psychogenesis (a new discipline), 1966 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - Distributional Requirements and Guidelines, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - "Education in a University" - Howell-Smith, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Extension Courses at Yale?, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Faculty of Arts and Sciences:
      - Age Distribution, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 73)
      - Years of Service, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - Faculty List, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - The Graduate School:
      - "Effect of Federal Actions Upon One…", 1971 (Box 11, Folder 76)
      - Questions re: Admissions and Federal Aid, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 77)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Housing", 1969 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - "Harvard's Student Strike: Politics of Mass Mobilization" - Urban Research Corp., 1970 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Housing - Five Year Survey - Joe Ford, 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - "Human and Social Benefits of Higher Education" - Draft, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - "Issues of Educational Reform" - Student Committee on Teaching of Yale University, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Law Schools - Articles by Bob Stevens, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Lipset and Ladd. "The Divided Professoriate" - fromChange, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Masters and Deans, interviews with Sara Ford, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Mayhew, Lewis B.: "Can Undergraduate Independent Study Courses Succeed?", 1971 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Memos from Members of the Study Group to the Study Group, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - News Clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - News Releases: Yale University News Bureau (selected releases), 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - President's Committee on General Education - Yale University, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Projection of Educational Statistics to 1970-80 - U.S. Office of Education, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - Proposal to the Carnegie and Ford Foundations M. Bressler, Princeton University, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - Redpath Proposal - the two platoon system, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Reference Articles, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - Reference Reports, Part I, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 95 - 96)
    - Reference Reports, Part II, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 97 - 98)
    - "Report on Housing to the Yale and New Haven Communities", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - Research Statistics - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - Residential Colleges, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - "Residential Colleges, as a Model for Governance" - M. Galligan, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 102)
    - Residential Colleges -The Physical Environment- L. Temoshok, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Residential Colleges:
      - "Report as Acting, Master of Silliman" - Hans Frei, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 104)
      - "Solicitation by Residential Colleges", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - "Sex Discrimination at Yale: A Document of Indictment", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 106)
    - Singer Reports - "A Bill of Obligations for Yale University", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - Statistics on Faculty, Admissions Activities, Postgraduate Plans, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - Stillman, Stanley - "Billington Letter" - views on higher education, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 109)
    - Student Center - "Proposal for the Renovation of Commons - Woolsey Hall", 1969 (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - "Student Protests: 1969 Summary"-Urban Research Corporation (Box 13, Folder 111)
    - Study of the City, etc. course descriptions, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 112)
    - Survey Data for Final Report, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 113)
    - Survey/Questionnaires - Doug Bennett, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 114)
    - Surveys:
      - White Male Freshmen, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 115)
      - White Female Freshmen, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 116)
      - Black Freshmen (Males and Females), 1971 (Box 13, Folder 117)
      - White Male Undergraduates, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 118)
      - While Female Undergraduates, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 119)
      - Minority Male Undergraduates, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 120)
      - Minority Female Undergraduates, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 121)
      - Alumni, Class of 1967, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 122)
      - Alumni, Class of 1961, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 123)
      - Preliminary Results:Profiles of Yale College, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 124)
      - Yale, Harvard, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 125)
    - Teaching and Learning Committee, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    - Teaching-Learning: "From Tension to Community…", undated (Box 14, Folder 127)
    - Tenure - "Tenure 1971" fromAAUP (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - Tuition Postponement - Abstract of Proposal to H.E.W., undated (Box 15, Folder 129)
    - Tuition Postponement, Questions and Answers, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 130)
    - University of Manchester - Report on Student Participation in Council Affairs, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 131)
    - Venturi and Rauch Studio Project: "Remedial Housing for Architects", 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 132)
    - "What is an Undergraduate Education at Yale?" Committee on Teaching, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 133)
    - "Whither United States Universities?"Science- George E. Pake, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Wiedersheim, William A. "Old Blues - Past, Present, Future", 1971 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Yale and the Community - Working Paper: Housing, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 136)
    - Yale College Finances, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Yale College Goals - Griswold Report, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Yale College Programs of Study and Special Programs for Freshmen and Sophmores, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Yale College Students, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Yale Historical Statistics - George Pierson, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - Yale Residential College Fellowships - D.A. Bromley, Chairman, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Yale University:
      - Council - Interim Reports, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 143)
      - Department File Activity Register, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 144)
    - Financial Material:
      - Budget and Accounting, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 145)
      - Receipts, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 146)
- Profiles of Yale College, 1971; Accession 2001-A-182
  - Profiles of Yale College: Surveys Conducted for the Study Group on Yale College, 1971 (Box 1)